Finding Aid for the Akira Togawa Papers LSC.1711
UCLA Library Special Collections
Akira Togawa papers
1921-1980
UCLA Library Special Collections
Togawa, Akira, 1903-
LSC.1711
27.5 Linear Feet (55 boxes and 3 oversize boxes)
Akira Togawa was born July 5, 1903. He came to the United States in 1923 and married his wife, Kimi, who was a kibei, in 1929, and they had five children. Before World War II, Togawa was employed by the M.S. Miura Company. During the war he was interned at Poston, Arizona, and after the war, he operated the Brooklyn & Ford Market in East Los Angeles. Active in various literary groups, including the Posuton Bungei, the Nanka Bungei, and the Sounsha he also wrote two poetry anthologies: Shishu (1932) and Mitsubachi no Uta (1962). He frequently contributed to local Japanese newspapers and poetry anthologies. The collection consists of diaries, correspondence, publications, which include a complete set of the Nanka Bungei, and newspaper clippings. Also includes copies of the works of other Japanese poets and writers. The entire collection is in Japanese.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Glenn Noboru Togawa, 1993.
Funding
This online finding aid has been funded in part by a grant from the Library Services and Technology Act (LSTA).
General note
[characters] indicates Japanese characters included in the print version of this online finding aid, available for consultation at the UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections.
General note
[characters] indicates Japanese characters included in the print version of this online finding aid, available for consultation at the UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9932225443606533
Biography
Akira Togawa was born July 5, 1903; he came to the United States in 1923; married his wife, Kimi, who was a kibei, in 1929, and they had five children; before World War II, Togawa was employed by the M.S. Miura Company; during the war, interned at Poston, Arizona; after the war, he operated the Brooklyn & Ford Market in East Los Angeles; he was active in various literary groups, including the Posuton Bungei, the Nanka Bungei, and the Sounsha; wrote two poetry anthologies: Shishu (1932) and Mitsubachi no Uta (1962); he frequently contributed to local Japanese newspapers and poetry anthologies; died in 1980.
Additional Biographical Narrative
Togawa Akira [characters]. 1903-1980. Issei poet and longtime resident of Los Angeles. Born July 5, 1903. Native, Yamanashi-ken, Minami Tsuru-gun, Funatsu-son, Aza Asakawa [characters]. Arrived in the United States in 1923. Father, Teiichi [characters]; mother, Shin [characters]. Father arrived alone in San Francisco, 1907. He returned to Japan in 1922, and came back to America with his son, Akira, the following year. In 1929 Akira married his wife, Kimi [characters], a Kibei woman. The couple had five children: daughter, Akiko [characters], 1930; son, Paul Susumu [characters], 1932; daughter, May Hiroko [characters], 1937; daughter, June Tomiko [characters], 1941; and son, Glenn Noboru [characters], 1946. Before the Second World War, Akira was employed by the M.S. Miura Company [characters], a Los Angeles wholesale produce company. Interned at Poston, Arizona during the war. Operated the Brooklyn & Ford Market in East Los Angeles in the postwar period.
Active in various Issei literary groups of Southern California before World War II, the Posuton Bungei [characters] during the war, and the Nanka Bungei [characters] after the war. Also member of the Sounsha [characters], a poetry society in Japan led by Ogiwara Seisensui [characters] who published the works of Issei poets. Also acquainted with many established Japanese poets and writers such as Oyama Sumita [characters], Uchijima Hokuro [characters], Yoshikawa Eiji [characters], and others. Author of two poetry anthologies: Shishu [characters], 1932, and Mitsubachi no Uta [characters], 1962 (for the latter, see the Japanese American Research Project Collection (Collection 2010), Box 364). Frequent contributor to local Japanese newspapers and poetry anthologies.
The Togawa Akira Papers include diaries, 1921-1978, 57 volumes; incoming correspondence file, 1962-1980; copies of prewar, wartime, and postwar Issei literary journals, including a complete set of the Nanka Bungei, poetry anthologies, novels and essays, autobiographies and biographies, and other books; copies of the works of Ogiwara Seisensui, Oyama Sumita, Uchijima Hokuro, Yoshikawa Eiji, and many other Japanese poets and writers; and 6 oversize scrapbooks of newspaper clippings on art and literature, 1952-1978. The collection of Issei poetry anthologies is outstanding.
by Yuji Ichioka and Makoto Arakaki
Scope and Content
Collection consists of diaries, correspondence, publications, and newspaper clippings related to the life of Akira Togawa. Diaries span 1921-78 in 57 volumes. Publications include pre-World War II, wartime, and postwar Issei literary journals, including a complete set of the Nanka Bungei. Also includes copies of the works of Ogiwara Seisensui, Oyama Sumita, Uchijima Hokuro, Yoshikawa Eiji, and other Japanese poets and writers. Oversize scrapbooks contain clippings related to art and literature, 1952-78.
The entire collection is in Japanese.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Diaries and notebooks (Boxes 1-7).
Incoming correspondence file, 1962-80 (Boxes 8-9).
Prewar literary publications (Boxes 10-11).
Wartime journals, essays, and anthologies (Boxes 12-13).
Postwar publications (Boxes 14-32).
Works of Japanese poets and writers (Boxes 33-55).
Newspaper clippings albums, 1952-78 (Boxes 56-58).
Related Material
Japanese American Research Project Collection of Material about Japanese in the United States (Collection 2010). Available at the Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
=Japanese American Research Project - Fading Footsteps of the Issei (Collection 2010). Available at the Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
American literature -- Japanese American authors -- Archives.; Japanese American poetry -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Japanese Americans -- Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945; Diaries.; Togawa, Akira, 1903- --Archives.
- Diaries, 1921-1978
  - 1921-1929. (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - 1930-1939. (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - 1940-1948. (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - 1949-1956. (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
  - 1957-1964. (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
  - 1965-1972. (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - 1973-1978. (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - Notebooks, 1921 & 1937. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Incoming Correspondence File
  - 1962-1966. (Box 8, Folder 1-6)
  - 1962-1980. (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
- Prewar Literary Publications
  - Agosutosha [characters], Taimatsu [characters], Tokyo: Sanshusha,; Haganuma Mitsuru [characters], Shishu: Aoba Moyuru Kokyo [characters], Fukushima: Hoppo Shijinkai, 1933 1934. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Hayashida Morio [characters], Doko e Iku [characters], Tokyo: Taijisha,; Iwanaga Tomoki [characters], Goshaku wo Idete [characters], Tokyo: Shimposha,; Mita Heihachi [characters], Ashiato [characters], Los Angeles: Mita Heihachi, 1928 1936 1936. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Nagaoka Shigure [characters], Shishu Saizaru [characters], Honolulu: Shogyo Jihosha,; Nagaoka Shigure [characters], Shishu Furusato [characters], Honolulu: Shogyo Jihosha, 1936 1937. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Naneikai [characters], Kashu: Nanko [characters], Los Angeles: Naneikai,; Naneikai [characters], Kashu: Seiun [characters], Los Angeles: Naneikai, 1934 1930. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Numata Rihei [characters], Shishu: Konna no Ga [characters], Tokyo: Koeisha,; Okina Kyuin [characters], Michi Naki Michi [characters], Tokyo: Koshisha Shobo, 1929 1928. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Shimoyama Eitaro [characters], Kiribue [characters], n.p.,; Shimoyama Eitaro [characters], Umi Hedate [characters], Morioka: Shimoyama Shiro, (see also the Japanese American Research Project Collection (Collection 2010), Box 366)., n.d. 1935 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Togawa Akira [characters], Shishu [characters], Los Angeles: Togawa Akira,; Yamazaki Isshin [characters], editor, Amerika Bungakushu [characters], Tokyo: Keigansha, 1932 1937. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Yamazaki Isshin [characters], editor, Amerika Bungeishu [characters], Tokyo: Kawamoto Tetsuo,; Yamazaki Isshin [characters], editor, Hokubei Bungei Senshu [characters], Tokyo: Bungei Hihyosha, 1930 1926. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Yamazaki Isshin [characters], editor, Horo no Shi [characters], Los Angeles: Horo no Shisha, 1925. (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Wartime Journals, Essays and Anthologies
  - Doto [characters], no. 2, (1944). (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Kagawa Bunichi [characters], Zuihitsu: Waga Mishi Hoho [characters], Tule Lake: Tessakusha, 1945. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Posuton Bungei [characters]:, March, August & October 1943; February, April, July & September 1944; and January, February & May-September 1945. (Box 12, Folder 3-6)
  - Posuton Kinseikai [characters], Kinseiryu Shiginshu [characters], Poston: Kuronikurusha,, v. 1; Shusui [characters], Shomon wo Kazaru [characters], Poston, 1944 1944. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Sugita Kokuho [characters], editor, Kokufuryu Shiginsen [characters], Tule Lake: Kinyusha, 1945. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Yao Yoshio [characters], Kashu: Kiganshu [characters], Tule Lake: Yao Yoshio, 1945. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Postwar Publications
  - A. Journals
    - California Tanka [characters], 1:1; 12:2-4, (1979) (1990). (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Koronia Bungaku [characters], nos. 10-12 and nos. 14-15, (1969-70) (1971). (Box 14, Folder 2-3)
    - Nanka Bungei [characters], nos. 1-3, (1965-66). (Box 14, Folder 4-6)
    - Nanka Bungei [characters], nos. 4-9, (1967-69). (Box 15, Folder 1-6)
    - Nanka Bungei [characters], nos. 10-16, (1970-73). (Box 16, Folder 1-7)
    - Nanka Bungei [characters], nos. 17-23, (1973-76). (Box 17, Folder 1-7)
    - Nanka Bungei [characters], nos. 24-30, (1977-80). (Box 18, Folder 1-7)
    - Nanka Bungei [characters], nos. 31-34, (1981-84). (Box 19, Folder 1-4)
    - Nichibei Tanka [characters]:, January, March, May, July, September & November 1962; January, March, May, July, September & November 1963; January, March, May, June & July 1964; and January, March & Summer 1965. (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
    - NY Bungei [characters], no. 9 (see also Japanese American Research Project Collection (Collection 2010), Box 355); Sakuhinsho [characters], nos. 4-5; Totem [characters],, Seattle., (1965) (1977-78) April 1928 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Tachibana [characters]: (see also Japanese American Research Project Collection (Collection 2010), Box 356)., April 1960; January, April, July & October 1963; January, April, July & October 1964; April & July 1965; January & October 1968; January, April, July & October 1969; April & July 1970; and October 1974 (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
  - B. Poetry Anthologies
    - Akahori Masaru [characters], Gyosei: Nichieidoku Taiyaku [characters], Los Angeles: Town Crier,; Ebihara Naoko [characters], Kashu: Orenji no Yokuya [characters], [Tokyo]: Shinsei Shobo, 1967 1961. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Furuya Kumatsugu [characters], Suikei Kushu: Ryuten [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha,; Hagio Imosaku [characters], Imin no Uta [characters], Matsyama: Daikosha,; Hashida Toyokaki [characters], Senninsho: Hayashida Toyoko Kushu [characters], [Kochi]: Kochi Nichibei Kyokai, 1958 1961 1960. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Hattori Naoyuki [characters], Godo Kashu: Reimei [characters], Los Angeles: Rocky Tanka Kai,; Hattori Naoyuki [characters], editor, Godo Kashu: Rokki Sankei [characters], Los Angeles: Rokki Tanka Kai,; Hirata Kocho [characters], Aru Seinen no Shuki: Kocho Bungeishu Dai-Isshu [characters], Okayama: Senryu Okayamasha, 1970 1974 1970. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Hirose Yoshi [characters], Mizu Mogusa [characters], Tokyo: Tanaka Shunji,; Hokubei Haikushu Henshu Iin [characters], Hokubei Haikushu [characters], Los Angeles: Tachibana Ginsha,; Hosaka Misao [characters], Yume no Hana [characters], Osaka: Kadono Atsuko, 1963 1974 1959. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Iwami Hisashi [characters], Kushu: Ebi Kago [characters], Los Angeles: Amerika Jojoha no Kai,; Iwata Masakazu [characters], Kashu: Shirobara [characters], Los Angeles., 1978 [1969?]. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Uwate Matao [characters], Watakushi no Sasayaki [characters], Los Angeles: Radio Little Tokyo,; Kato Harue [characters], Taiko no Hibiki [characters], Tokyo: Shinsei Shobo,; Kazato Toyo [characters], Kabunshu: Chigiregumo [characters], Tokyo: Nihon Bungeisha, 1962 1970 1965. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Kunitsugu Shiro [characters], Zenbei Senryu Jisen Kushu [characters], Los Angeles: Kaku Senryu Ginsha,; Matsue Hisashi [characters], Matsue Hisashi Uta Kareki [characters], Los Angeles: Amerika Jojoha no Kai,; Matsumoto Tomiko and Matsumoto Ryokuyo [characters], Kashu: Mishigan Kohan [characters], n.p.: Shinsei Shobo, 1960 1982 1960. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Miki Ken [characters], Hadoson no Sasayaki [characters], Tokyo: Nihon Bungeisha,; Miki Ken [characters], Sasurai no Uta [characters], Tokyo: Nihon Bungeisha, 1964 1960. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Morita Minako [characters], Otto: Yoshitake wo Shinobi [characters], n.p.,; Nagata Setsuko [characters], Matsubazue no Rojin [characters], Fukuoka: Yuri Kakai, n.d. 1949. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Nanka Bungeisha [characters], Kagawa Bunichi Shishu [characters], Los Angeles: Nanka Bungeisha, 1982. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Nishi Masago [characters], Dogguuddo no Hana [characters], Osaka: Hakujusha,; Nishimura Masamoto [characters], Izumi no Uta: Nishimura Yoshimi Ikoshu [characters], Seaside: Nishimura Masamoto,; Nixon, Lucille M. and Tana, Tomoe, Sounds from the Unknown, Denver: Alan Swallow, 1974 1971 1964. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Nozawa Miyoko [characters], Suiren [characters], Matsuyama: Daikosha,; Okada Hanako [characters], Hana ni Hana [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha,; Otsuki Yoshisaburo [characters], Shimo no Hana [characters], Matsuyama: Oyama Sumita, 1962 1961 1979. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Rafu Kinseikai [characters], Izumi [characters], Los Angeles: Rafu Kinseikai, 1947. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Sakai Yoneo [characters], Sakai Yoneo Shishu [characters], Tokyo: Shichosha, 1966. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Taira Kaibaseki [characters], Dai-Goju no Hoshi [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha,; Takahashi Kyoko [characters], Kozan [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1962 1962. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Takeda Roji [characters], Takeda Roji Kashu [characters], Tokyo: Shinsei Shobo,; Tanaka Shurin [characters], Dancho Hyakuin [characters], [Denver]: Nakamura Baifu,; Tokunaga Takeko [characters], Yukyo Sannen: Tokunaga Takeko Kushu [characters], Los Angeles: Jiryusha,; Tomari Yoshihiko [characters], Kashu: Ryojin [characters], Kagoshima: Nichibei Tankasha, 1970 1952 1948 1958. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Totsukuni Tankakai [characters], Kashu: Ishokurin [characters], San Francisco: Totsukuni Tankakai,; Tsumura Mokuyo [characters], Waga Hitotsu no Tomoshibi [characters], Oakland: Popii Ginsha,; Tsuneishi Shisei [characters], Hokubei Hototogisu Nyusen Kushu [characters], Hollywood: Tachibana Ginsha, 1958 1953 1951. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Tsuneishi Shisei [characters], Kushu: Kiku no Chiri [characters], Los Angeles: Tsuneishi Shisei,; Usuda Yoko [characters], editor, Nire no Ochiba: Usuda Tenjoshi no Ikushu [characters], n.p.: Privately printed,; Yagata Keizan [characters], Kushu: Agehacho [characters], Okayama: Senryu Okayamasha, 1975 1957 1972. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Yakaranda no Kai [characters], Yakaranda no Kai: Dai-Ichi Jiyuritsu Kushu [characters], Los Angeles: Yakaranda no Kai, 1976. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Yamaguchi Bokuson [characters], Kushu: Karihonia [characters], [Los Angeles]: Privately printed,; Yamaguchi Chiyo and Yamaguchi Hideo [characters], Yashi no Hazure [characters], Tokyo: Shinsei Shobo, 1966 1977. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Yasuda Hakuhanshi [characters], editor, Hokubei Hototogisu Nyusen Dai-Ni Kushu [characters], Los Angeles: Tachibana Ginsha, 1958. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Yonekura Hisae [characters], Hana to Kumo [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha,; Yonekura Hisae [characters], Hanazukuri no Ku [characters], Tokyo: Daisenen,; Yonekura Hisae [characters], Hayashi no Edamichi [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1960 1941 1965. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Yonekura Hisae [characters], Matsu no Ki to Tomo ni [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha,; Yonekura Hisae [characters], Yonekura Hisae Dai-Go Kushu [characters], Kyoto: Sounsha, 1970 1977. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - C. Novels and Essays
    - Fujita Akira [characters], editor, Nanka Bungei Senshu, 1965-1980 [characters, 1965-1980], Los Angeles: Nanka Bungeisha,; Fujita Akira [characters], Nochi no Kokei [characters], Tokyo: Renga Shobo Shinsha, 1981 1982. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Koronia Bungakukai [characters], Koronia Shosetsu Senshu [characters], Sao Paulo: Koronia Bungakukai,; Matsushita Iwao [characters], Neko no Negoto [characters], Tokyo: Nihon Shuppan Boeki Kabushiki Kaisha,; Nagata Setsuko [characters], Wagahai wa Inu de Aru [characters], Fukuoka: Yuri Kakai, 1978 1966 1952. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Nanka Bungeisha [characters], Okidokei: Zuihitsushu [characters], Los Angeles: Nanka Bungeisha, 1983. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Nomoto Ippei [characters], Shihen Danso [characters], Los Angeles: Privately printed,; Okazaki Ginko [characters], Sarinasu no Tsuchi [characters], Tokyo: Chuo Koron Jigyo Shuppan, 1976 [1965?]. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Sakai Yoneo [characters], Nikkei Shimin Yuki [characters], Tokyo: Sankei Shimbunsha Shuppankyoku,; Sekiguchi Nobara [characters], Koga no Mizu ga Kiyoku Naru Made [characters], Shimizu: Nihon Shingaku Remmei,; Tsuchiya Chikano [characters], editor, Tsuioku Tokoro Dokoro: Suiho Tsuchiya Rinpei Iko [characters], Nara: Tenrikyo Shimposha, 1969 1965 1961. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Yamashita Jonin [characters], Waga Yo no Haru [characters], Tokyo: Jitsugyo no Nipponsha Jigyo Shuppanbu,; Yamazaki Seiichi [characters], Rafu Shimpo Mokuyobi Zuiso: Bijo to Bishu [characters], Los Angeles: Yamazaki Seiichi, 1954 1975. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - D. Internment Life Accounts
    - Nakamura Kenta [characters], Kokansen [characters], Tokyo: Shinwasha,; Noda Kasen [characters], Posuton Tenjuki [characters], Los Angeles: Nippon Shoten,; Noda Nobuo [characters], Manzana no Arashi [characters], Los Angeles: Noda Nobuo,; Sasaki Shuichi (Sasabune) [characters], Yokuryujo Seikatsuki [characters], Los Angeles: Rafu Shoten,; Yamamoto Asako [characters], Ibara Aru Hakudo [characters], n.p.: Privately printed, 1966 1968 1971 1950 1952. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - E. Autobiographies and Biographies
    - Akagi Teiji [characters], Tobei Gojunen no Ashiato [characters], Los Angeles: Privately printed,; Asano Shichinosuke [characters], Zaibei Yonjunen [characters], Tokyo: Yuki Shobo,; Ishida Tenkai [characters], Kijutsu Gojunen [characters], Tokyo: Asahi Shimbunsha, 1966 1962 1961. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Japanese Community Pioneer Center, Ayumi no Ato [characters], nos. 1-2, (1973 & 1975). (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Kasai Hiroshi-O Yawa Kanko Iinkai, [characters], Kasai Hiroshi-O Yawa [characters], Yokohama: Kanko Iinkai,; Kobayashi Fumio [characters], Shimoyama Isso no Shogai to Sono Geijutsu [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha,; Masuoka Ryuei [characters], Omoi no Mama ni [characters], Kyoto: Shimizu Hideo, 1955 1954 1969. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Mihara Tokinobu [characters], Shiroi Tsue ni Tayori Tsutsu [characters], San Francisco: Toyo Bunkasha,; Mitoma Toshichi and Yoshie [characters], Zaibei Rokujunen no Kaiso [characters], Tokyo: Kirisuto Shimbunsha, 1963 1970. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Niisato Kanichi [characters], Yami ni Hirameku Koe Naki Koe [characters], Tokyo: Shimposha, 1934. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Sasaki Shuichi (Sasabune) [characters], Amerika Seikatsu [characters], Los Angeles: Taishusha,; Sasaki Shuichi (Sasabune) [characters], Hariuddo no Kijin: Tanaka Shurin [characters], Los Angeles: Taishusha, 1937 1938. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Sodei Rinjiro [characters], Yumeji Kashu Kyakuchu [characters], Tokyo: Shueisha,; Takahashi Aiko [characters], Kaisen Kara no Nikki, 1941-1955 [characters, 1941-1955], Tokyo: Takahashi Aiko, 1985 1955. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Takahashi Aiko [characters], Meiji Hyakunen ni Omou [characters], Tokyo: Takahashi Aiko,; Takahashi Aiko [characters], Saikai no Tabi [characters], Tokyo: Takahashi Aiko, 1972 1965. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Tomimoto Iwao [characters], Tohenboku [characters], Tokyo: Kokusai Heiwa Sangyokai,; Yamada Nyose [characters], Wasuregusa [characters], Mitsugi: Miyoshi Gesshu, 1961 1970. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - F. Yamanashi Prefecture Materials
    - Hirose Shurei [characters], Zaibei Koshujin Funto no Gojunenshi [characters], Los Angeles: Nanka Yamanashi Kaigai Kyokai,; Hawai Yamanashi Kenjinkai Kaiho [characters], no. 20, 1934 (1951). (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Ito Kenkichi [characters], Kawaguchi Kohan Funatsu Konjaku Monogatari [characters], Funatsu: Ide Kozai,; Nanka Yamanashi Kenjinkai [characters], Nanka Yamanashi Kenjinkai Jushoroku [characters],; Kayanuma Hideo [characters], Kawaguchi-Ko Choshi [characters], Kawaguchi-Ko Cho Yakuba,; Yamanashi Kenjinkai Tobo: Kakushu Amachi Tenjusho Oyobi Kinko [characters], Granada Relocation Center, Amache, Colorado, 1952 1952, 1957 & 1961 1966 1945. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - G. Religion
    - Akahoshi Kimiko [characters], Iwanaga Emiko Sensei [characters], Los Angeles: Niji no Ie,; Habato Nikoruson [characters], Yagi no Ojisan [characters], Tokyo: CLC Kurashi no Hikari Sha, 1954 1974. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Iijima Kanjitsu [characters], Ikita Bukkyo [characters], Tokyo: Tosei Shuppansha,; Kondo Choei [characters], Kirisuto Monogatari [characters], Los Angeles: Kondo Shizuko,; Kubose Gyomei [characters], Soto yori Uchi e: Shikago ni Ikiru Bukkyo [characters], Chicago: The Dharma House, 1953 1959 1972. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Nozaki Reikai [characters], Kagiri Naki Inochi [characters], Los Angeles: Nozaki Reikai,; Ono Jotetsu [characters], Kesso Kaio Monogatari [characters], Olive View: Ono Jotetsu, 1955 1962. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Sekiguchi Nobara [characters], Bungei to Shukyo [characters], Tokyo: Seishin Kagakusha,; Sekiguchi Nobara [characters], Kagaku to Shukyo: Uchu to Ai e no Kito [characters], Tokyo: Seishin Kagakusha, 1963 1962. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Sekiguchi Nobara [characters], Nihon Shinto Shingaku [characters], Shimizu: Nihon Shingaku Remmei,; Senzaki Nyogen [characters], Amerikajin no Bukkyo [characters], Tokyo: Okura Shuppan Kabushiki Kaisha,; Sutanre Jonsu [characters], Kito no Hoho [characters], Los Angeles: Shinsei Kyokai Shuppanbu, 1955 1955 1946. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - H. Miscellaneous
    - Abe Toyoji [characters], Toki no Kage [characters], San Francisco: Abe Yuka,; Adachi Fudehiro [characters], Hawai Nikkeijinshi [characters], Tokyo: Ashi-no-Ha Shuppankai,; Aoki Hisa [characters], Kanashimi wa Umi no Kanata ni: Amerika kara no Tegami [characters], Tokyo: Sumiyoshi Shoten,; 442nd Veterans Association of Southern California, 100th - 442nd Directory, Los Angeles: 442nd Veterans Association of Southern California, 1968 1977 1953 1967. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Furuya Suikei [characters], Imin no Rakugaki [characters], Honolulu: Hawai Taimuzusha,; Hasegawa Shinichiro [characters], Zaibei Hojin no Mitaru Beikoku to Beikokujin [characters], Tokyo: Jitsugyo no Nihonsha, 1968 1937. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Hashimoto Henri [characters], Sekai no Tabi Tsurezure [characters], Los Angeles: Ajia Ryokosha,; Kondo Choei [characters], Kondo Choei Ikoshu [characters], Los Angeles: Kondo Shizuko, 1971 1970. (Box 31, Folder 3)